ragan.com 2008-12-17

# Privacy Policy | Core Pages | Privacy Policy | Leaders in corporate communications and internal communication | Lawrence Ragan Communications

**Privacy Policy**

Protecting your privacy is important to us. We hope the following statement will help you understand how Ragan Communications collects, uses and safeguards the customer information you provide to us on our Web site. 

  * Information Collection  

  * Information Use  

  * Declining E-mail Offers  

  * Company Commitment to Privacy  

  * Internet Communication  

  * Linked Internet Sites  

  * Consent  

  * Changes to the Internet Privacy Statement  

 **  
Information Collection**

When you browse ragan.com and have not registered for any online service from Ragan, you browse anonymously. Personal informationâ€”such as your name, address, phone number or e-mail addressâ€”is not collected as you browse. Ragan may, however, use "cookies" to collect information about how our site is used. Information, such as the server your computer is logged onto, your browser type (for example, Netscape or Internet Explorer), and whether you responded to a Ragan banner ad or e-mail may be collected and tracked in aggregate. This information is used for the purpose of measuring response rates to banner ads and e-mail offers. Registration for Online Products and Services. In order to provide you with a particular product or service online, we may request that you voluntarily supply us with personal or company information, including your e-mail address and customer number, for purposes such as correspondence, site registration, checking your account status, Invoices, statements and other pertinent information online, making a purchase, or participating in online surveys and enabling us to provide an online product or service to you in an efficient manner. If you are known to us as a registered user of a Ragan online service, we may combine information about your use of ragan.com or other Ragan websites and the online products or services you utilize with certain other online and offline information we have about you as an Ragan customer and information you have provided to us as well as information available from external sources, such as trial subscription data, in order to customize your online experience and present you with relevant online and offline offers and updates. We also may use a "cookie" to enable our server to recognize you as a registered Ragan online service user when you re-enter our site.   
  
**Information Use**

We may use information you have given us to, for example, provide a service, ensure proper product deliveries or billing, measure consumer interest in our various services and inform you about products and services. If you have provided your e-mail address to us or to a company we've partnered with to make their products and services available to you, we may send you e-mail offers. We may also send you e-mail offers if you have provided your e-mail address to a third party and have actively chosen or requested, on an opt-in basis, to receive e-mail offers from other parties. These offers may be based on information you provided in your initial transaction with us, in surveys, from information that may indicate purchasing preferences as well as information available from external sources. These e-mail offers come directly from Ragan. You can opt out from receiving e-mail offers from Ragan Communications as described below in the section, Declining e-mail offers. When we send e-mails to you, we may be able to identify information about your e-mail address, such as whether you can read graphic-rich HTML e-mails. If your e-mail address is HTML-enabled, we may choose to send you graphic-rich HTML e-mails. Please note that we do not provide your e-mail address to Ragan business partners. However, we may send you offers on behalf of our Ragan business partners. Keep in mind that if you take advantage of an offer from a Ragan business partner and become their customer, they may independently wish to send offers to you. In this case, you will need to inform them separately if you wish to decline receiving future offers from them.  
  
 **Declining E-mail Offers**

Ragan provides customers with an easy means to decline receiving e-mail offers. Although some customers will appreciate receiving notice of these carefully designed opportunities, we recognize the importance of providing you with choices. At any time, you may request to discontinue receiving these offers from us by changing your preferences online, via the [My Account](http://www.qfie.com/ragan2/clsRAGANlookup.asp?Tok=OxcyonRaganQuickfill2&strAspReason=201&URL=http://www.ragan.com/ME2/Sites/load.asp?AudID=C9AF08199DF9479CA33AD783205471FA&SiteID=) page if you are a subscriber. If you are a free eNewsletter subscriber you will need to unsubscribe from each appropriate publication in order to ensure no further offers. See eNewsletter Terms of Use for additional information. All e-mail offers that you received from Ragan will inform you of how to decline receiving further e-mail offers.   
  
**Company Commitment to Privacy**

This Ragan Communications Customer Internet Privacy Statement applies to all visitors to our website. If you have questions about our online Privacy Statement or your account, please call Ragan Communications at 800.878.5331 or 312.960.4100.   
  
**Internet Communication**

We at Ragan Communications are committed to the secure transfer of information via our website and take all current technological steps to ensure that, however communication over the Internet cannot be guaranteed, because the Internet is not a completely secure medium. We do not assume responsibility for any harm, loss, or damage you may experience or incur by the sending of personal or confidential information over the Internet by or to us.  
  
 **Linked Internet Sites**

You should be aware that other Internet sites to which you link from ragan.com may contain privacy provisions that differ from the provisions of our Privacy Statement.   
  
**Consent**

By using this site, you signify your consent to this on-line privacy policy. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not use this site. Ragan Communications reserves the right, at its discretion, to update, change, modify, add, or remove portions of this policy from time to time. Any changes to this privacy policy will be promptly disclosed in this area.   
  
**Changes to the Internet Privacy Statement**

Changes to our Internet Privacy Statement will be noted here so that you can be fully informed about the privacy protections we provide and your choices with regard to our use of personal information for marketing purposes. 

(Sample Change)   
Date: 1/01/05   
Section: Information Use   
Description: This section was updated to reflect the fact that we do NOT share e-mail addresses with other companies. In addition, it reflects the fact that we may provide customers with graphic-rich HTML e-mails if we know if their e-mail address is HTML enabled.
